Portraits of prominent men in art, law, politics, and government
Prints & Photographs Division, Library of Congress
Portraits of prominent men in art, law, politics, and government ca. 1940-ca. 1970
LOT 13309
Young, Katherine, d. 1993, photographer.
171 photographic prints: gelatin silver, b&w; 34 x 26.5 cm. or smaller.
Prints & Photographs Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
These formal portraits of national and international figure--diplomats, statesmen, and political figures--are featured prominently throughout the LOT.
For information about Prints and Photographs Division collections and services, see the Prints & Photographs Division's Reading Room Home Page.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Young, Katherine, d. 1993, photographer.
Subjects
Architects--1940-1970.; Artists--1940-1970.; Diplomats--1940-1970.; Government officials--1940-1970.; Men--1940-1970.; Politicians--1940-1970.; Statesmen--1940-1970.
Form/Genre
Gelatin silver prints--1940-1970.; Portrait photographs--1940-1970.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift; Katherine Young; 1985; (DCL/PP-1985:197).
Additional form available
Digitized images of some items in the collection and their associated identifying information are available through the Prints & Photographs Online Catalog, by searching using the call number "LOT 13309."
Scope and Content Note
Formal portraits of national and international figures. Diplomats, statesmen, and political figures are featured prominently throughout the LOT. Includes some portraits of U.S. Supreme Court justices, architects, and artists. Also one portrait of Alice Acheson and one of Mary Rockefeller (Mrs. Nelson Rockefeller).
Organized/Arranged
Photographs are organized by size into two subdivisions. LOT-13309-1 has the smaller prints designated (F); LOT 13309-2 has the larger prints designated (H). A single alphabetical index for both sizes serves as the container list
http://lccn.loc.gov/99472032
Container List
- Acheson, Alice, LOT 13309-1, no. 1 (F)
- Acheson, Dean, LOT 13309-1, no. 2 (F)
- Al-Amri, Mohammet, LOT 13309-1, no. 3 (F)
- Alsop, Joseph, LOT 13309-1, no. 4 (F)
- Alsop, Stewart, LOT 13309-1, no. 5-6 (F)
- Austin, Warren Robinson, 1877-, LOT 13309-1, no. 7 (F)
- Baroody, J.M., LOT 13309-1, no. 8 (F)
- Belaunde, Victor Andres, 1883-, LOT 13309-1, no. 9-10 (F)
- Bellegarde, Dantes, 1877-1966, LOT 13309-1, no. 11 (F)
- Berendson, Carl, LOT 13309-1, no. 12 (F)
- Black, Eugene R. (Eugene Robert), b. 1898, LOT 13309-1, no. 13-14 (F)
- Blanco, Carlos, LOT 13309-1, no. 15-16 (F)
- Blume, Peter, 1906-, LOT 13309-2, no. 1 (H)
- Bokhari, Ahmed Shah, LOT 13309-1, no. 17 (F)
- Bouche, Louis, 1896-1969, LOT 13309-2, no. 2 (H)
- Bourguiba, Habib, 1903-, LOT 13309-1, no.18-19 (F)
- Bracco, Darwin, LOT 13309-1, no. 20-21 (F)
- Breton, Andre, 1896-1966, LOT 13309-1, no. 22 (F)
- Brooke, Edward William, 1919-, LOT 13309-1, no. 23-24 (F)
- Bunshaft, Gordon, 1909-, LOT 13309-1, no. 25-26 (F)
- Carias Andino, Tiburcio, 1876-, LOT 13309-1, no. 27-28 (F)
- Castro, Hector David, LOT 13309-1, no. 29 (F)
- Catton, Bruce, 1899-, LOT 13309-1, no. 30 (F)
- Chapman, Oscar L. (Oscar Littleton), 1896-1978, LOT 13309-1, no. 31 (F)
- Chaves, Osvaldo, LOT 13309-1, no. 32 (F)
- Clark, Tom C. (Tom Campbell), 1899-1977, LOT 13309-1, no. 33 (F)
- Clifford, Clark M., 1906-, LOT 13309-1, no. 33 (F)
- Corbett, Harvey Wiley, 1873-1954, LOT 13309-1, no. 35 (F)
- Cornwell, Dean, 1892-1960, LOT 13309-1, no. 36 (F)
- Cornwell, Dean, 1892-1960, LOT 13309-2, no. 3 (H)
- Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952, LOT 13309-1, no. 37 (F)
- Davila, Carlos G., 1887-1955, LOT 133091, no. 38 (F)
- Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960, LOT 13309-1, no. 39 (F)
- Dillon, C. Douglas (Clarence Douglas), 1909-, LOT 13309-1, no. 40-42 (F)
- Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-, LOT 13309-1, no. 43 (F)
- Du Boise, Guy Pene, 1884-1958, LOT 13309-1, no. 44 (F)
- Duke, Angier Biddle, 1915-1995, LOT 13309-1, no. 45-46 (F)
- Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959, LOT 13309-1, no. 47-51 (F)
- Dun, Angus, 1892-1971, LOT 13309-1, no. 52-54 (F)
- Duncan, Jephtha, LOT 13309-1, no. 55-56 (F)
- Eban, Abba Solomon, 1915-, LOT 13309-1, no. 57-59 (F)
- Eggers, O.R. (Otto Reinhold), 1882-1964, LOT 13309-1, no. 60 (F)
- Evergood, Philip, 1901-1973, LOT 13309-2, no. 4 (H)
- Intizam, Nasr Allah, 1900 or 1901-, LOT 13309-1, no. 61-62 (F)
- Fawzi, Mahmoud, LOT 13309-1, no. 63 (F)
- Feininger, Lyonel, 1871-1956, LOT 13309-1, no. 64-65 (F)
- Ferriss, Hugh, 1889-, LOT 13309-1, no. 66-67 (F)
- Franco, Francisco, 1892-1975, LOT 13309-1, no. 68-71 (F)
- Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965, LOT 13309-1, no. 72 (F)
- Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-, LOT 133091, no. 73-74 (F)
- Goldberg, Arthur J., LOT 13309-1, no. 75-76 (F)
- Gonzalez, Cesar, LOT 13309-1, no. 77 (F)
- Graham, Billy, 1918-, LOT 13309-1, no. 78 (F)
- Greunther, Alfred, LOT 13309-1, no. 79 (F)
- Hammarskjold, Dag, 1905-1961, LOT 13309-1, no. 80 (F)
- Harmon, Arthur Loomis, LOT 13309-1, no. 81 (F)
- Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986, LOT 13309-1, no. 82 (F)
- Henriquez Urena, Max, 1885-, LOT 13309-1, no. 83 (F)
- Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978, LOT 13309-1, no. 84 (F)
- Jackson, Robert Houghwout, 1892-1954, LOT 13309-1, no. 85 (F)
- Jean, Jose de, LOT 13309-1, no. 86 (F)
- Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines, 1908-1974, LOT 13309-1, no. 87-88 (F)
- Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963, LOT 13309-1, no. 89 (F)
- Khalida, Awni, LOT 13309-1, no. 90-91 (F)
- Knowland, William F. (William Fife), 1908-1974, LOT 13309-1, no. 92 (F)
- Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974, LOT 13309-1, no. 93 (F)
- Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, LOT 13309-1, no. 94 (F)
- Lavalle, Juan Bautista de, 1887-1970, LOT 13309, no. 95-96 (F)
- Lavalle, Carlos Holquin de, LOT 13309-1, no. 97-98 (F)
- Levine, Jack, 1915-, LOT 13309-2, no. 5 (H)
- Maldarelli, Oronzio, 1892-1962, LOT 13309-2, no. 6 (H)
- Malik, Charles Habib, 1906-, LOT 13309-1, no. 99-100 (F)
- Mangravite, Peppino, 1896-, LOT 13309-1, no. 101-102 (F)
- Mansfield, Mike, 1903-, LOT 13309-1, no. 103-105 (F)
- Manship, Paul, 1885-1966, LOT 13309-1, no. 106-107 (F)
- Mattson, Henry, LOT 13309-2, no. 7 (H)
- McCloy, John Jay, 1895-, LOT 13309-1, no. 108-110 (F)
- McNamara, Robert S., 1916-, LOT 13309-1, no. 111-113 (F)
- Miller, Henry, 1891-, LOT 13309-1, no. 114-115 (F)
- Minton, Sherman, 1890-1965, LOT 13309-1, no. 116 (F)
- Montgomery of Alamein, Bernard Law Montgomery, Viscount, 1887-1976, LOT 13309-1, no. 117-121 (F)
- Moore, Henry, 1898-, LOT 13309-1, no. 122 (F)
- Mora, Jose Antonio, LOT 13309-1, no. 123 (F)
- Muniz, Joao Carlos, LOT 13309-1, no. 124 (F)
- Narathipphongpraphan, Prince, grandson of Mongkut, King of Siam, 1891-1976, LOT 13309-1, no. 125 (F)
- Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-, LOT 13309-2, no. 8 (H)
- Orozco, Jose Clemente, 1883-1949, LOT 13309-2, no. 9 (H)
- Quintanilla, Luis, 1900-1980, LOT 13309-1, no. 126 (F)
- Ramirez, Boettner Luis Maria, 1918-, LOT 13309-1, no. 127 (F)
- Restrepo Jaramillo, Jose, LOT 13309-1, no. 128 (F)
- Reuters, Ernst (Dr., Mayor/Berlin), LOT 13309-1, no. 129 (F)
- Richter, Gerhard, LOT 13309-1, no. 130 (F)
- Rockefeller, Mrs. Nelson, LOT 13309-1, no. 131-132 (F)
- Rusk, Dean, 1909-, LOT 13309-1, no. 133-134 (F)
- Sanchis Quevedo, Antonio, LOT 13309-1, no. 135 (F)
- Sawyer, Charles, b. 1887, LOT 13309-1, no. 136-137 (F)
- Schmid, Carlo, LOT 13309-1, no. 138 (F)
- Slim, Mongi, LOT 13309-1, no. 139 (F)
- Sloan, John, 1871-1951, LOT 13309-1, no. 140-141 (F)
- Snyder, John W. (John Wesley), 1895-1985, LOT 13309-1, no. 142-144 (F)
- Solorzano, Luis Mena, LOT 13309-1, no. 145-146 (F)
- Sparkman, John, 1899-1985, LOT 13309-1, no. 147-149 (F)
- Speicher, Eugene Edward, LOT 13309-1, no. 150 (F)
- Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965, LOT 13309-1, no. 151-152 (F)
- Thomen, Luis, LOT 13309-1, no. 153 (F)
- Thors, Thor, LOT 13309-1, no. 154 (F)
- Tobin, Maurice J., LOT 13309-1, no. 155-156 (F)
- Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972, LOT 13309-1, no. 157 (F)
- Tsiang, Tingfu Fuller, 1895-1965, LOT 13309-1, no. 158-159 (F)
- Villeda Morales, Ramon, 1908-, LOT 13309-1, no. 160 (F)
- Warren, Earl, 1891-1974, LOT 13309-1, no. 161 (F)
- Zorach, William, 1887-1966, LOT 13309-2, no. 10 (H)